<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-07T22:30:27-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Lindsey Anne | Portfolio</title><subtitle>Blog, portfolio, etc.</subtitle><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><entry><title type="html">The wonderful power of social media</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/the-wonderful-power-of-social-media" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The wonderful power of social media" /><published>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/the-wonderful-power-of-social-media</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/the-wonderful-power-of-social-media">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;An email exchange.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sun, May 3, 2020 at 11:05 AM \
From: Jeffrey David Hooven	\
To: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:runongirlrunon@gmaildotcom&quot;&gt;runongirlrunon@gmaildotcom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear Lindsey,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hearing from a person who appreciates the music you wrote years ago is like running into an old friend.  Thank you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m attaching some sheet music for you.  Of course, the music I’ve written in the past several years is different in many ways from my earlier music, so I will also send you a video of a piece I wrote for my wife, Karen Lorraine.  It’s called “My Sweet Lorraine.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you keep playing and creating!  Best wishes, and thanks again for your incredible support.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace and love,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeffrey David&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4 attachments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cambria.pdf 1690K&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Judith.pdf 742K&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jakes Blues.pdf 777K&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Morning Meditation.pdf 3497K&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thu, May 7, 2020 at 10:01 PM \
From: &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:runongirlrunon@gmaildotcom&quot;&gt;runongirlrunon@gmaildotcom&lt;/a&gt;	\
To: Jeffrey David Hooven&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Jeffrey David,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been meaning to respond all week but this one has been pretty tough. Hence, I cannot express how absolutely joyed I am to receive this email. Let me tell you a bit of the saga I’ve gone through the last few years; I’m sure you’ll appreciate it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, I finally acquired an electric piano. I’d grown up playing an upright my parents bought for me to learn on, but after moving out I never had the space for a keyboard. I asked my mom if she still had all the books I used to have when I was younger, and she said they’d either ended up with a family member or donated somewhere. I didn’t mind because I could always find the books again, or so I thought. There was one I sort of remembered the name of but couldn’t find it for the life of me; it had a song in it called “Cambria” but I couldn’t recall the composer’s name either. I thought the book was called “Keyboard Classics” and had a rainbow on the front, but all the googling of every combination of words I could think of just led me to modern tabs from a band called “Coheed and Cambria.” Not quite right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I tried several times over the last few years to track this book down or the song or anything about it, but nothing ever came up. Then, a couple weeks ago, I tried posting again on Reddit about it and finally SOMEONE FOUND THE BOOK. After finding the title, “The Spectrum Collection of Colorful Keyboard Classics,”  I managed to track down someone selling both volumes on Amazon. One of the listings (volume II) had a typed-out list of the songs, some of which were absolutely familiar, but nowhere did I see the name “Cambria.” I wrote to the Amazon seller asking if they could send me photos of the song indexes in both books. While waiting for a response, I kept going back to the listing, trying to see if anything could jog my memory… and finally it clicked. Jeffrey David Hooven! So, I went googling again, found some random archive of Instagram posts that lead me to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BqyfTYjHaUg/?igshid=u79ew092dbv1&quot;&gt;video of the woman playing “Morning Meditation.”&lt;/a&gt; That song was definitely familiar, and that’s when I figured out that your daughter’s name was Cambria, so I figured I was just mixing up pieces of memories. Hence, I reached out, thinking I had found the song…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then your email showed up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sat down and played “Cambria” tonight twice in a row for the first time in probably 15 years. This was an absolutely special moment to experience after a years-long search for this piece of music. Playing piano has always been so dear to me, as it’s one of the ways my grandmother and I bonded when I was young–she was my first teacher, and I will always cherish the memories of sitting at her baby grand trying to access the talent I inherited from her.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has been one of the hardest weeks I’ve ever gone through, but this moment changed it for the better in so many ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you. So so so much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the best,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lindsey Anne&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">An email exchange.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From the archives: Burying Your Dead Code</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-burying-your-dead-code" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From the archives: Burying Your Dead Code" /><published>2019-06-06T16:20:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T16:20:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-burying-your-dead-code</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-burying-your-dead-code">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Another post from my time on the Data Engineering team at Grand Rounds, I think posted in January 2017. Their engineering blog has disappeared recently, but thankfully I saved my writing in my notes. I’ve edited it slightly for readability in the code block. Enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As our code evolves and changes, little bits of leftovers from refactors or changed paths can build up as dead code. It’s like the plaque that builds up on your teeth over time: not really noticeable at first, but after an occasional trip to the dentist, you feel a whole lot better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the dead parts from your codebase is a simple process at its core: find the dead parts, prove that they’re dead, and delete them. The tricky part is in that second step, but after a little trial and error, we discovered a couple tricks to speed up the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;start-small&quot;&gt;Start small&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before digging into a gigantic repo to see what you can rip out of there, consider the impact of what you’re about to do and start with just a small piece of it. Because I was investigating one of our biggest repos, I decided to tackle a single Model first rather than, say, the entire lib directory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;finding-the-dead-parts&quot;&gt;Finding the dead parts&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m sure there are other gems out there that perform similar assessment, but our favorite gem for this is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/seattlerb/debride&quot;&gt;debride by Seattle Ruby Brigade&lt;/a&gt;. It’s not 100% perfect, but it will give you a good place to start digging around. The whitelisting option is particularly helpful after your initial investigation. Another option is the brute-force method, where you comb through a file and investigate each piece one by one. If your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;debride&lt;/code&gt; output is suspiciously large, this might be worth a try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;prove-that-theyre-dead&quot;&gt;Prove that they’re dead&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the fun part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The specific service I was trying to clean up is one of our oldest repositories, and some of the functions that were showing up as dead ends had been sitting in there for months or even years. What’s a girl to do, dig through hundreds and thousands of pull requests and commits until coming up with the right one? Oh no, we have a tool for that. It’s called &lt;a href=&quot;https://git-scm.com/docs/git-bisect&quot;&gt;git-bisect&lt;/a&gt;, and it’s one of the coolest things I’ve learned so far about git.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git-bisect&lt;/code&gt; is generally used for tracking down when a bug was introduced by using a binary search through as many commits as you’d like; you can start at the very beginning of your git history or somewhere in the middle. It checks out the repo at each commit, where you can test your issue and mark it as “good” or “bad.” Rather than testing for a bug, though, I used it to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; for the method names that were appearing as dead from my previous step one at a time. If &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;grep&lt;/code&gt; only gave one result (barring tests that might still exist), then nothing else was calling the method anymore and I’d mark it “bad.” If it showed up with more results, I’d mark it “good.” The point when searching for a bug is to find the last “good” commit before a bug was introduced; the point when using it to look for dead code is to track down when the consumer was removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example to illustrate the steps you’ll take to do the same thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;~/my_repo [master] $ git bisect start

~/my_repo [master] $ git bisect bad

~/my_repo [master] $ git bisect good ecef47e2fefc4c8ac6f3a358a4961332d24a46e3
Bisecting: 4825 revisions left to test after this (roughly 12 steps)
[0a9fc468c6efb6465c9fa96232b9f61dee01a12b] Merge pull request #5902 from my_repo/branch_5902

~/my_repo [:0a9fc46|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:0a9fc46|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 2412 revisions left to test after this (roughly 11 steps)
[d30229d184d5e93d39683b1f129745a211368890] Merge pull request #5346 from my_repo/branch_5346

~/my_repo [:d30229d|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:d30229d|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 1205 revisions left to test after this (roughly 10 steps)
[d116a5bf4d26ad1e33a099b5027883d16bbe68f2] changed a thing

~/my_repo [:d116a5b|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:d116a5b|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 602 revisions left to test after this (roughly 9 steps)
[ff2693d90e72798abbb8adbf57f331e661b6445b] fixed a bug

~/my_repo [:ff2693d|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:ff2693d|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 296 revisions left to test after this (roughly 8 steps)
[c6e79d2aa3185774be46473f51027d65aca6216e] Merge pull request #5040 from my_repo/branch_5040

~/my_repo [:c6e79d2|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:c6e79d2|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 152 revisions left to test after this (roughly 7 steps)
[74a8add547a62de49d535df07587703186057f24] Merge pull request #5017 from my_repo/branch_5017

~/my_repo [:74a8add|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:74a8add|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 68 revisions left to test after this (roughly 6 steps)
[c0d8f4c89964e95b5e5a823d0ecf36533a8c67b0] Merge pull request #5008 from my_repo/branch_5008

~/my_repo [:c0d8f4c|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:c0d8f4c|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 42 revisions left to test after this (roughly 5 steps)
[2a26af52b5c6234709f9816425c2cb3be7c1d3c3] changed error handling

~/my_repo [:2a26af5|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:2a26af5|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 21 revisions left to test after this (roughly 5 steps)
[37f592be9e75a68a497055109047d2e8d478cc64] Merge pull request #5038 from my_repo/branch_5038

~/my_repo [:37f592b|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:37f592b|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 10 revisions left to test after this (roughly 4 steps)
[6af2e9adc4556d153436880fb4f25e6cfa33dda0] move this thing

~/my_repo [:6af2e9a|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:6af2e9a|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 5 revisions left to test after this (roughly 3 steps)
[9ad36a544f3995e85556e9f58561d648c503ce47] added a thing

~/my_repo [:9ad36a5|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:9ad36a5|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 2 revisions left to test after this (roughly 2 steps)
[1ede562f1ab630df8b6a14dd3177413373738dca] fixed a bug

~/my_repo [:1ede562|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/helpers/my_helper.rb:    old_method_consumer = (model.try(:old_method_name) || model.try(:something_else?))
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:1ede562|…15375] $ git bisect good
Bisecting: 0 revisions left to test after this (roughly 1 step)
[8d15ccfd9d7fb0b0a6609ad87af4f5cc5566ee21] Merge pull request #5039 from my_repo/branch_5039

~/my_repo [:8d15ccf|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:8d15ccf|…15375] $ git bisect bad
Bisecting: 0 revisions left to test after this (roughly 0 steps)
[c62e10dbe9436b9a7ad5afd37e495414591f3160] fixed another bug

~/my_repo [:c62e10d|…15375] $ git grep old_method_name
app/models/my_model.rb:  def old_method_name

~/my_repo [:c62e10d|…15375] $ git bisect bad
c62e10dbe9436b9a7ad5afd37e495414591f3160 is the first bad commit
commit c62e10dbe9436b9a7ad5afd37e495414591f3160
Author: Jane Doe &amp;lt;jane@doe.com&amp;gt;
Date:   Thu Mar 3 12:34:56 2016 -0800

    Refactored a thing

:040000 040000 8a3d0400211d91920ea2caba83cf73f80c858b3f b39651a7ef882af4e5be2fe6f2a06a5baa4cccbe M    app

~/my_repo [:c62e10d|…15375] $
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;delete-them&quot;&gt;Delete them&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, I finally found the commit where the diff showed the changed or removed method call; thus, I could remove the call in my current branch. After deleting all the dead code, I made sure to comment on each removed function in my pull request with the commit number where the consumer was removed (because documentation is rad). Many code reviews later, our Model was done with her teeth cleaning and felt just a little bit better.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Another post from my time on the Data Engineering team at Grand Rounds, I think posted in January 2017. Their engineering blog has disappeared recently, but thankfully I saved my writing in my notes. I’ve edited it slightly for readability in the code block. Enjoy!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">From the archives: Learning to Sight Along the Space Capsule</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-learning-to-sight-along-the-space-capsule" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="From the archives: Learning to Sight Along the Space Capsule" /><published>2019-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2019-06-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-learning-to-sight-along-the-space-capsule</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/from-the-archives-learning-to-sight-along-the-space-capsule">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was originally published on 2016-12-29 when I was on the Data Engineering team at Grand Rounds. Enjoy!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Testing does not have to be complicated, but sometimes it can turn into spaghetti just like any other code. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=URSWYvyc42M&quot;&gt;This talk&lt;/a&gt; by Sandi Metz at Railsconf 2013 inspired me to revisit some of the unit tests for one of our services that relies heavily on FTP and SFTP connections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;why-are-my-tests-failing&quot;&gt;Why are my tests failing?&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous test suite for this service used a gem that was originally created as a mocked framework for testing FTP connection behaviors. However, a few key problems existed with this solution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The gem hasn’t been maintained in a couple years, which started to cause intermittent spec failures.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The gem doesn’t support SFTP connections, which our service relies much more heavily on than FTP.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The gem doesn’t actually mock anything. It starts up a local FTP server, runs the tests, and then shuts the server down. Each test that’s run against it is generating a real response, albeit locally. This not only took up a lot of time (starting and stopping the local server before and after each spec), but was also another source of intermittent failures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, after creating a plan of attack, I rewrote or deleted every single test that used this gem. Each test was also re-evaluated for “sighting along the space capsule,” as Sandi Metz calls it. Any test that was written for a private method, a message sent to the object’s self, or an implementation detail was scrutinized (and most of them deleted), which exposed the true underlying issue: almost every single test we’d written that used the gem was an &lt;em&gt;implementation&lt;/em&gt; test, not an &lt;em&gt;interface&lt;/em&gt; test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;External responses are supposed to be completely mocked out in unit testing, not make actual calls to an API or server. Tests exist to make sure &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; code works as expected, not to verify that no errors are raised when making external requests. A unit test that requires a response from an outside source is already a broken test; save those for integration tests instead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;reframing-our-point-of-view&quot;&gt;Reframing our point of view&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an example to illustrate my point. Let’s say we have an object whose job is to get a list of files from a specific folder on an FTP server. For brevity’s sake, let’s define it like this, with the nitty gritty details fleshed out elsewhere:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    class FtpThing
      def get_list_of_files(username, password, folder_name)
        @some_connection.open(username, password)
        list_of_files = @some_connection.list(folder_name)
        @some_connection.close
        list_of_files
      end
    end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, one option for testing this is the way we did it before, something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    let(:ftp_thing) { FtpThing.new }
    let(:list) { [‘file1.txt’, ‘file2.txt'] }

    before do
      # spin up the “mock&quot; (real) server
      # put a (real) file or two in a folder on the server
    end

    it ‘gives me the right list of files’ do
      expect(ftp_thing.get_list_of_files(‘username’, ‘password’, ‘folder_name’)).to eq(list)
      ftp_thing.get_list_of_files(‘username’, ‘password’, ‘folder_name’)
    end

    after do
      # shut down the server
    end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the surface, this doesn’t look terrible. It’s testing the value returned from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;getListOfFiles&lt;/code&gt;, right? Yay, that’s what we want! But… not quite. We’ve started a real server, and we hope that a) it started in time for our tests to run, and b) it doesn’t fail or raise any errors, which is how our tests will pass. Instead, we need to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;allow&lt;/code&gt; a mocked response and set up our expectation this way:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    let(:mock_connection) { double(‘ftp’) }
    let(:ftp_thing) { FtpThing.new }
    let(:list) { [‘file1.txt’, ‘file2.txt'] }

    before do
      ftp_thing.set_instance_variable(:@some_connection, mock_connection)
      allow(mock_connection).to receive(:open)
      allow(mock_connection).to receive(:list).and_return(list)
      allow(mock_connection).to receive(:close)
    end

    it ‘gives me the right list of files’ do
      expect(ftp_thing.get_list_of_files(‘username’, ‘password’, ‘folder_name’)).to eq(list)
      ftp_thing.get_list_of_files(‘username’, ‘password’, ‘folder_name’)
    end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the difference? We aren’t starting a server or making a real external call; we’re just pretending that it happened and gave us the right response. The true test is whether &lt;em&gt;our&lt;/em&gt; code is giving us the right value back after it makes an external call. This is also an easy way to test error responses, too! I can allow my connection to raise an error, and then test my error handling from there, rather than trying to fake out a whole server thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bonus points: If I want to change the implementation of my server call–maybe I want to change how it connects or opens the connection, or something similar–then my tests are not broken and I can continue on my merry way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;the-moral-of-the-story&quot;&gt;The moral of the story&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No project is complete without some beautiful numerical data to back it up, so here’s some numbers to show off just how much time this saves us. Running the entire test suite on the application before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Finished in 2 minutes 56.1 seconds (files took 2.72 seconds to load)
    172 examples, 0 failures
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And after:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;    Finished in 5.67 seconds (files took 2.77 seconds to load)
    155 examples, 0 failures
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s a &lt;em&gt;97% time improvement.&lt;/em&gt; Precious minutes of time regained, and no more intermittent failures as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story? Don’t make real calls to real servers in your tests, even if they’re local to your machine or CI container. Set up mocked responses when needed, and test that &lt;em&gt;your&lt;/em&gt; code is actually working, not theirs. (And seriously: watch that talk by Sandi Metz at least three more times until it really sticks. Your future self will thank you.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">This post was originally published on 2016-12-29 when I was on the Data Engineering team at Grand Rounds. Enjoy!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh, hi there.</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/oh-hi-there" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh, hi there." /><published>2018-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2018-10-09T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/oh-hi-there</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/oh-hi-there">&lt;p&gt;It’s been just over a year since I updated this thing, so, figure it’s about time to post something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-life-update&quot;&gt;Quick life update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last year has been a whirlwind. Moved into my first big kid apartment in November, graduated with my BS in CS from SFSU in December, took my mom on my first trip overseas to Rome in February, adopted an adorable little rescue pibble named Isis in April, released records with both of my two bands (within a week of each other, actually) in September. The other day, one of my bands opened for one of my favorite bands at one of my favorite venues, so I’m going to be riding that high for a while. Life is fantastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;quick-work-update&quot;&gt;Quick work update&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m still working at Grand Rounds on the Data Engineering team. We’ve been busy over the last quarter or so launching v2.0 of our insurance claims pipeline. The part of the project I’m responsible for is building a service that creates production-quality test data. I didn’t intend to follow the fun “neighborhood” theme we’ve had going on with some of our recent repos, but my PM pointed out last week that calling my project the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;laundromat&lt;/code&gt; has done exactly that. (Whatever, it’s cute.) I’m building it as a Ruby script (without Rails, which has been an interesting exercise) that reads from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;STDIN&lt;/code&gt;, scrubs each line of in file and replaces all the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Personally_identifiable_information&quot;&gt;PII&lt;/a&gt; with fake names/addresses/etc., and then writes it back to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;STDOUT&lt;/code&gt; in the same format as the input. The purpose is to get us high quality data for testing our system without leaking any personal information from our patients. Huge shoutout to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ryanwood&lt;/code&gt; for writing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ryanwood/slither&quot;&gt;slither gem&lt;/a&gt; because it’s made my work about 300% easier; funny how a gem that hasn’t been updated in 6+ years can still provide so much value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also been practicing a lot of string/file/IO manipulation using the command line, so even though most of my work focus is Ruby-based, I figure it’s probably a good idea to share some of the other fun things I learn here while I go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;using-diff-for-sanity-checks&quot;&gt;Using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; for sanity checks&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each insurance vendor’s file format that we ingest, I need to build a JSON file that tells my &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Laundry::Machine&lt;/code&gt; (believe me, the analogy gets sillier as I go) what &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Laundry::Detergents&lt;/code&gt; are needed to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;#scrub&lt;/code&gt; each line of the input. My process for development is basically:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create the JSON file and add whatever metadata I need to it (fixed width file vs. CSV, what the delimiters are for lines and columns, etc.).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;List the column headers from the vendor’s data dictionary.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test to ensure I’m getting the correct in/output when not changing anything.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Indicate the transformations and test my in/output again to ensure the data still looks okay.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Generate a new test file and put it through our development pipeline to see if anything breaks.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Report any bugs to the rest of the team.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rinse and repeat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mentioned earlier that the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;laundromat&lt;/code&gt; needs to write the same format as it reads in; this is important mostly because that’s where Claims Pipeline v1.0 ran into many bugs as we built it. Line endings could be weird (thank you Windows for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;\r\n&lt;/code&gt;), whitespace could be important or unimportant, fixed width files are generally a pain in the rear, etc. The test files we built previously were hand-edited to remove PII, and text editors sometimes like to remove things that are actually really important to control for in our production system, so we ran into several occasions where a file would stop moving through the pipeline due to some special case we weren’t expecting. Hence, when designing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;laundromat&lt;/code&gt;, I wanted to ensure I’m getting the &lt;em&gt;exact&lt;/em&gt; same input and output when I’m not doing any transformations on the data. That’s where &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; comes in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In step 3, I’ll generally use one of our previously-created sample files, let’s call it &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;$SAMPLE_FILE&lt;/code&gt; for now. Now, I knew that &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; could take two files as arguments, but what I didn’t know is that it can also take the output of a command, like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(command_one) &amp;lt;(command_two)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;()&lt;/code&gt; is the bash-specific &lt;em&gt;substitution&lt;/em&gt; syntax, which passes the output of whatever is inside to the input of wherever you’re directing it. It’s handy when you can’t use pipes, like with our friend &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; up there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Further, you can add all kinds of fun stuff inside the parentheses to dig deeper into whatever you’re trying to do. Generally, though, I’ll just start with a single line of my sample file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE) &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | ./laundromat.rb vendor_name)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this produces no output, I can go on my merry way to step 4 of my dev cycle. If it does, though, it’s time to start adding things into my diff command to figure out exactly what I missed. Usually the first thing from here is to pipe the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;diff&lt;/code&gt; output into &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;less&lt;/code&gt; with the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-S&lt;/code&gt; option, which will paginate the output horizontally, so I can (hopefully) visually see exactly where it’s not lining up between the input and output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE) &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | ./laundromat.rb vendor_name) | less -S
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I don’t see anything obvious right away, I’ll add more stuff to figure out which field is giving me trouble. Since it’s a CSV, I can replace the column delimiters with a newline and then run the diff on that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | tr , '\n') &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | ./laundromat.rb vendor_name | tr , '\n')
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If this &lt;strong&gt;still&lt;/strong&gt; doesn’t show me anything obvious, like in this example:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | tr , '\n') &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | ./laundromat.rb vendor_name | tr , '\n')
63c63
&amp;lt; &quot;46912003601220&quot;
---
&amp;gt; &quot;46912003601220&quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;then I get to bust out another tool I love called &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;od&lt;/code&gt;, which stands for “octal dump”. Adding the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-c&lt;/code&gt; option makes it show me the actual characters from the input, so it’s more obvious what I’m looking at and I don’t have to decipher which character &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;031466&lt;/code&gt; stands for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ diff &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | tr , '\n' | od -c) &amp;lt;(head -1 $SAMPLE_FILE | ./laundromat.rb vendor_name | tr , '\n' | od -c)
36,37c36,37
&amp;lt; 0001060    1   2   0   0   3   6   0   1   2   2   0   &quot;  \r  \n        
&amp;lt; 0001076
---
&amp;gt; 0001060    1   2   0   0   3   6   0   1   2   2   0   &quot;  \n            
&amp;gt; 0001075
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And there we have our culprit–the freakin’ Windows carriage return. (╯°□°）╯︵ ┻━┻ Now I can control for that in my script and head forward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;well-that-was-fun&quot;&gt;Well, that was fun&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to publish more of these style of blog posts, because if nothing else they’re pretty fun to write (and, I hope, more entertaining to read than StackOverflow). Stay tuned!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">It’s been just over a year since I updated this thing, so, figure it’s about time to post something.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Notes from #GHC17</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/notes-from-ghc17" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Notes from #GHC17" /><published>2017-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-10-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/notes-from-ghc17</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/notes-from-ghc17">&lt;p&gt;I’m writing this from the plane on my way home from my first time attending the annual Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing. My thoughts are still sort of scattered but I wanted to get some of it down before life back on the ground gets too distracting again. (I swear I have a half-finished post about SFHacks that’s coming too…)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/runongirlrunon/status/916710749594095617&quot;&gt;tweeted&lt;/a&gt; a bit about all of it earlier today but that was before my coffee had kicked in so I wasn’t sure how to fully process what I was thinking about. I finally managed to pin down that my dominant feeling today has been somewhere between unfulfilled and impatient. I’ve been trying to figure out the source of it since I woke up, and I think it comes from two places: not getting to do enough stuff/see enough sessions at the conference due to the weird block scheduling, and a solidification of the nagging feeling I’ve had that I have got a &lt;strong&gt;lot&lt;/strong&gt; of work ahead of me in my career.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:50.0% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZ0-VQwglTH/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Here we gooooo! #ghc17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by miss lindsey (@runongirlrunon) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-10-04T13:26:16+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 4, 2017 at 6:26am PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opening keynote was more inspiring than I had expected it to be (which made me wonder why I was expecting it to be less than that in the first place). A couple highlights:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/drfeifei&quot;&gt;Dr. Fei-Fei Le&lt;/a&gt; made me reconsider what it means to be human. Not my own humanity, but the humanity inherent in the things we create. We call it “artificial intelligence” and give it to robots and machines… but there’s still something human at its center, because it is &lt;em&gt;created&lt;/em&gt; by humans.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I was absolutely impressed and humbled by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/Dr_Black&quot;&gt;Dr. Sue Black, OBE&lt;/a&gt; speaking so frankly and honestly about the horrible experiences she had before her career in tech began. How many people do you hear walk out in front of 18,000 people and open with a story about their then-spouse’s death threats? And after all she’s been through, she just seems so pleasant and warm. Truly a resilient being.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;So many cheers for &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/melindagates&quot;&gt;Melinda Gates&lt;/a&gt; on all points. Her humor and wit are unrivaled; her brain is a force to be reckoned with. #NoMoreMemos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One really huge thing I got out of this week is that my dreams got a lot bigger by the end of it, partially due to talking with Marilyn, who is a software engineer at Blue Origin. I hadn’t deeply considered that someday I might get to build rockets or the software that rocket launching teams use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Turns out that even the people who build spaceships and rockets are just regular people like you and me. I managed to catch &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/runongirlrunon/status/915980981462585346&quot;&gt;a panel of five awesome women&lt;/a&gt; who work in various aerospace companies speaking about their jobs, and I learned that it’s just like any other software engineering job, just with different risks involved. That, in turn, made me realize that there’s a lot of industries I hadn’t considered pursuing before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The sky is the limit on where I could find myself in the future–and maybe that isn’t even the limit, because I could one day build something that goes into outer space. Eight-year-old me who used to love staring at the stars and learning about planets is SUPER excited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most inspiring talk I saw was featured speaker Stephanie Lampkin, CEO of Blendoor, telling the story of how she came from less-than-stellar beginnings (drug addict mom, never met her dad, grew up poor), made her way through Stanford and MIT, and still managed to get told that she “wasn’t technical enough” when she applied for an advanced technical role at Google. “We’ll call you when we get a sales or marketing position for you.” Ummm, excuse me? One of her many “twirls” (which is a MUCH better word than “pivot”) that eventually led her to create her own company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite quote was during the audience Q&amp;amp;A when she was talking about unconscious bias: “Unconscious bias is not unconscious; it’s conscious. These men know what they’re doing and they just &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/runongirlrunon/status/916003312922701824&quot;&gt;don’t give a fuck&lt;/a&gt;.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3o6gaUYip73ooXZWEw/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;beyonce twirling gif&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite career guidance talk just happened to be the last day of the conference. The session was called “So You Want To Be An Executive?” A panel of five executive-level leading women shared their experiences of how their lives and careers and even day-to-day jobs changed after moving from management into executive roles. I took a &lt;strong&gt;LOT&lt;/strong&gt; of notes, which I have tried to condense for this post as best I could, but it’s hard to condense an hour of incredibly valuable life advice into a few paragraphs. The takeaways, which I’ve paraphrased from the speakers:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;tammarrian-rogers-qa-director-of-engineering-at-snap-inc&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tammarrian&quot;&gt;Tammarrian Rogers&lt;/a&gt;, QA Director of Engineering at Snap, Inc.&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Your values should always be at the center of your decisions. When you can truly define what your values are (i.e. what does it mean to value “family”? Do you value &lt;em&gt;time&lt;/em&gt; with them, do you value &lt;em&gt;providing&lt;/em&gt; for them, or something else?), then it becomes easier to make decisions and communicate your needs, and that is when you will thrive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leadership requires vision. That doesn’t mean &lt;em&gt;having&lt;/em&gt; all the answers; it means &lt;em&gt;finding&lt;/em&gt; the answers and steering the ship.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bring your whole self to the table every day.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember that every skill you have is applicable to your work–your outside life is in addition to your work life, not separate from it, so use what you learn outside to make yourself better in your career.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;rebecca-norlander-ceo-of-samepage-health&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/rebatwork&quot;&gt;Rebecca Norlander&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of SamePage Health&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remember: everyone puts on their pants one leg at a time.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leadership at the exec level (versus management level) means not doing the job of the people who are working for you anymore. If you’re doing that and you feel comfortable doing it, then you’re not doing your own job. (Tammarrian added that if you’re stepping into someone else’s role, then you’re not trusting them to do what you hired them to do. Good points all around.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The “Five P’s” is a really great rubric for designing how you’re going to manage a project. In order, you should define the &lt;strong&gt;purpose&lt;/strong&gt; of the project (why are we doing this?), the &lt;strong&gt;principles&lt;/strong&gt; by which you wish to operate, &lt;strong&gt;prioritization&lt;/strong&gt; of tasks (which requires actually telling people what the priorities are, because they might not know even if they seem obvious to you), &lt;strong&gt;plan&lt;/strong&gt; and process (how is this going to work, how do we move forward, what are we going to measure), and when you’ve got all that in order then you design your team, or your &lt;strong&gt;people&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Experimentation will naturally lead to failure. Your entire career will be built on learnings from failures, so don’t shy away from something because you’re afraid to fail.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turns out lots of people like to give advice, so finding a mentor isn’t actually that hard. What you often need are &lt;em&gt;sponsors&lt;/em&gt;–people who are not your direct manager(s) who will help other people know how awesome you are and back you up when you need it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactive and in-depth product reviews (not just status updates) will help you understand and lead parts of the business you are unfamiliar with. Understand the difficulties and the hot spots and the underlying architecture–you’re smart, so trust yourself to know how to gather the data and ask the right questions. (Tammarrian added to this that deep dives are critical to understanding not just the product but also the &lt;em&gt;people&lt;/em&gt; working on it and how they built it, why they made the decisions they did, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;alex-tibbetts-head-of-brand-moments-at-youtube&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/tibbea&quot;&gt;Alex Tibbetts&lt;/a&gt;, Head of Brand Moments at YouTube&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On executive presence: “Fill up the room.” But what does that mean? It means feeling like you own the place and not letting anyone or anything intimidate you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you need something you don’t have–invent it!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop your writing skills now, because people will remember your voice, and that may lead to good things for you down the road. (This is one of the ways she ended up in her role; an email she wrote started circulating, which got her name and voice recognition, and ultimately led people to know how great and capable she was at being a thought leader.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People will always judge you, so don’t spend your time worrying about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;liz-pearce-ceo-of-liquidplanner&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/lizprc&quot;&gt;Liz Pearce&lt;/a&gt;, CEO of LiquidPlanner&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You’re going to be stressed at any job, and it turns out the stress isn’t all that different whether you’re early in your career or whether you’re in an exec level position. So, you may as well aim high.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Growing your career is like developing calluses; every time you do it, you get a little tougher. Being uncomfortable is a sign that you’re growing. Also, it’s a marathon, not a sprint, so pace yourself and don’t burn out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Feelings and emotions are not permanent–good or bad–so don’t get attached to them.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;YouTube is really helpful for learning new skills, like finance and sales.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On sleeping at night with so many livelihoods depending on you: “Someone has to make all the hard decisions, so it may as well be you.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes you can literally just ask for a position. (This is how she became Director of Marketing at LiquidPlanner before eventually becoming CMO, COO, and then CEO.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&quot;gail-giacobbe-vp-of-product-management-at-godaddy&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ggiacobbe&quot;&gt;Gail Giacobbe&lt;/a&gt;, VP of Product Management at GoDaddy&lt;/h6&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Note: Gail mostly facilitated, but she also gave a few great pieces of advice during the audience Q&amp;amp;A.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mentorship can evolve into sponsorship, so keep those relationships alive.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Non-profits and volunteering can help you learn a lot, as most non-profits are microcosms of larger businesses that can help you expand and diversify your skillset.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;instagram-media&quot; data-instgrm-captioned=&quot;&quot; data-instgrm-version=&quot;7&quot; style=&quot; background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);&quot;&gt;&lt;div style=&quot;padding:8px;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:#F8F8F8; line-height:0; margin-top:40px; padding:37.4537037037037% 0; text-align:center; width:100%;&quot;&gt; &lt;div style=&quot; background:url(data:image/png;base64,iVBORw0KGgoAAAANSUhEUgAAACwAAAAsCAMAAAApWqozAAAABGdBTUEAALGPC/xhBQAAAAFzUkdCAK7OHOkAAAAMUExURczMzPf399fX1+bm5mzY9AMAAADiSURBVDjLvZXbEsMgCES5/P8/t9FuRVCRmU73JWlzosgSIIZURCjo/ad+EQJJB4Hv8BFt+IDpQoCx1wjOSBFhh2XssxEIYn3ulI/6MNReE07UIWJEv8UEOWDS88LY97kqyTliJKKtuYBbruAyVh5wOHiXmpi5we58Ek028czwyuQdLKPG1Bkb4NnM+VeAnfHqn1k4+GPT6uGQcvu2h2OVuIf/gWUFyy8OWEpdyZSa3aVCqpVoVvzZZ2VTnn2wU8qzVjDDetO90GSy9mVLqtgYSy231MxrY6I2gGqjrTY0L8fxCxfCBbhWrsYYAAAAAElFTkSuQmCC); display:block; height:44px; margin:0 auto -44px; position:relative; top:-22px; width:44px;&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;&quot;&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/p/BZ6y-qvA4l8/&quot; style=&quot; color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Dr. @tellewhitney, outgoing CEO of @anitaborginstitute, accepting her lifetime achievement award. I’m so honored to even be in a room with her. What an inspiration! #GHC17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p style=&quot; color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;&quot;&gt;A post shared by miss lindsey (@runongirlrunon) on &lt;time style=&quot; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;&quot; datetime=&quot;2017-10-06T19:42:31+00:00&quot;&gt;Oct 6, 2017 at 12:42pm PDT&lt;/time&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; defer=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;//platform.instagram.com/en_US/embeds.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The closing keynote was interesting and lively–a really great end to the week. We said goodbye to outgoing Anita Borg Institute President and CEO, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/TelleWhitney&quot;&gt;Dr. Telle Whitney&lt;/a&gt;, and welcomed her successor, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/BrendaDardenW&quot;&gt;Dr. Brenda Darden Wilkerson&lt;/a&gt; into the role. Awards were handed out, speeches were spoken, keynotes were presented, and facilitating it all with some amazing stand-up comedy-level humor was &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/NoraDenzel&quot;&gt;Nora Denzel&lt;/a&gt;. (By the way, if you’re reading this, Nora, I would like to personally invite you to facilitate literally everything ever from now until forever. You are my #LifeGoals.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now back to my original point of feeling unfulfilled and impatient. Really, the first part comes from wanting to do all the things and not getting to do them. (Seriously though, I’ll volunteer to help with scheduling next year if y’all are looking.) Eventually, one of us will invent a way to be in 20 places at once and solve that, though. The impatience is definitely due to coming away feeling so eager to get to work building even more cool shit than I’ve already built. Not just building software, too–building relationships, mentorships, my career in general! My mountain is waiting, time to get on my way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you next year, GHC!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Addendum: I should mention that one of the most important parts of GHC is actually the networking. I mostly wanted to focus this post on the talks I went to and the speakers I heard, but it cannot be said enough how valuable was the time I spent bonding with other women also fighting their way to make their way in technical roles. &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sisterhood is powerful.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">I’m writing this from the plane on my way home from my first time attending the annual Grace Hopper Celebration of Women in Computing. My thoughts are still sort of scattered but I wanted to get some of it down before life back on the ground gets too distracting again. (I swear I have a half-finished post about SFHacks that’s coming too…)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello, world.</title><link href="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/hello-world" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello, world." /><published>2017-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2017-08-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>https://runongirlrunon.github.io/hello-world</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://runongirlrunon.github.io/hello-world">&lt;p&gt;Welcome to my new blog, website, portfolio… whatever this might turn into. My plan here is to showcase my projects, mostly, but also to post the fun things I learn about Ruby, Rails, Git, or, I don’t know, maybe I’ll develop some unlikely passion for PHP along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To start things off, here’s a few blog posts I’ve written for Grand Rounds, the healthcare company I’ve been working for since May 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the Engineering blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20171216122447/http://eng.grandrounds.com/blog/2016/12/29/testing-against-external-services/&quot;&gt;Wayback Machine: Learning to Sight Along the Space Capsule&lt;/a&gt;. Inspired by Sandi Metz’s RailsConf 2013 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=URSWYvyc42M&quot;&gt;talk on unit testing&lt;/a&gt;, I reworked one of our service’s test suites that had been increasingly slowing down, improving its run time from ~3 minutes down to ~6 seconds.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Also on the Engineering blog, &lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20180703020715/http://eng.grandrounds.com/blog/2017/01/24/burying-your-dead-code/&quot;&gt;Wayback Machine: Burying Your Dead Code&lt;/a&gt;. Or, how I used &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git bisect&lt;/code&gt; to track down dead code in one of our main app’s Models.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the company news blog, I detailed a recent foray into leading a project in my post &lt;a href=&quot;https://news.grandrounds.com/blog/tearing-down-barriers-to-health-care-access-requires-focus-on-minority-groups/&quot;&gt;Tearing Down Barriers to Health Care Access Requires Focus on Minority Groups&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my next couple posts, I’ll expound on some projects I’ve worked on at school, such as the hackathon my team &lt;em&gt;Moon Latency&lt;/em&gt; won in April, and my brief experience as the “CEO of a small startup,” &lt;em&gt;Warehaus Media&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2019-06-06 edit: updated links to go to the Wayback Machine, as the GR Eng blog has been taken down. RIP.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lindsey Anne</name><email>runongirlrunon@gmail.com</email></author><summary type="html">Welcome to my new blog, website, portfolio… whatever this might turn into. My plan here is to showcase my projects, mostly, but also to post the fun things I learn about Ruby, Rails, Git, or, I don’t know, maybe I’ll develop some unlikely passion for PHP along the way.</summary></entry></feed>